JADE WANG

New York, NY 10001 | 626-376-0713 | jadewang425@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Full stack developer who recently completed a 12-week Software Engineering bootcamp with individual and group projects. 7 years of experience working in e-commerce and operations for high-end brands. Skilled in client-centric front-end development that provides appealing and user-friendly web interfaces.

TECHNICAL AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Bootstrap, Mongoose

Databases and other: Postman, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Node.js, RESTful Routing, JSON/APIs

Interpersonal skills: collaborative with cross-functional teams and 3-parties; bilingual: fluent in English and Mandarin

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Paw Circle - GitHub | App - React | Express.js | MangoDB/Mongoose

A MERN-stack, single-page application for organizing pet-centric meetups and fostering a vibrant community for pet owners.

- Integrated Mapbox API with an authentication token to implement address auto-fill and dynamic location display.
- Utilized Bootstrap and React components to create a visually appealing and responsive user interface.

Gym Grid - GitHub | App - Python | Django

A workout planner using the Django framework for customizing exercises for your workout routine.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 full-stack software engineers to perform CRUD functionality.
- Acted as project manager monitoring progress and code version control via GitHub.

Trip Planner - GitHub | App - JavaScript | Express.js | MangoDB/Mongoose

A user-friendly trip planner for users to organize tasks and add attendants with a comment feature.

- Implemented full CRUD functionality creating trips via Experss.js and MangoDB.
- Utilized Google OAuth for authentication and authorization to add and edit content.

An Animal Memory Game - GitHub | App - JavaScript | CSS | HTML

Interactive 1-player browser memory game with sound effects.

- Incorporated card flip animation using CSS to create a smooth and realistic interaction.
- Implemented sound effects and DOM manipulations in JavaScript to maintain the excitement of playing.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frette, E-commerce Specialist

New York, NY | 08/2022 - 02/2023

- Managed e-commerce performance analytics and maintained digital content delivery via SFCC and Google Analytics.
- Collaborated with developers in Agile methodology and ensured website issues are resolved in a timely manner.
- Leveraged A/B testing tools to promote personalizations and sale events to improve online shipping experience.

E-commerce Coordinator

Cartier

New York, NY | 09/2018 - 07/2022

- Managed end-to-end order fulfillment process in coordination with cross-functional teams to resolve e-commerce order issues and ensure on-time order delivery in partnership with the customer service team.
- Partnered with the Agile team to implement OMS including UAT to ensure requirements were met.

Operational Assistant Manager, Watch Marketing

- Oversaw watch business in analyzing product performance/inventory, producing and delivering new product launch communications, and implementing marketing initiatives in partnership with cross-functional teams.
- Implemented a five month retail sales incentive which resulted in +21% versus targeted product sales.

Stuart Weitzman, Retail Operations Coordinator

New York, NY | 05/2016 - 08/2018

- Oversaw store operations in 55 retail locations nationwide, including inventory management, supply chain and logistics, internal communications, policies and procedures.
- Managed store supply ordering process and lowered the supply costs by 40% compared to the previous year.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote | 10/2023

Certificate in Software Engineering

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN | 05/2016

Bachelor of Science in Retail Merchandising